Guide to the UE National Office Records Relating to District 5 and District 5 Locals, 1936-1983 UE.4.1.5
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- District 5 Locals, 2.
  - Local 523
    - Local 523 Publications, 1952-1953 (Box 6, Folder 139)
      - "Merry XMAS" Leaflet, 1952; 1.
      - "You Know Us" Leaflet, 1953; 2.
  - Local 524
    - Local 524 Officers List, November 30, 1943 - 1944 (Box 6, Folder 140)
    - Local 524 Incoming Correspondence, 1943 - 1955 (Box 6, Folder 141)
      - Bill Cahn to Roger Allchin Regarding Supplies, December 14, 1949; 1.
      - Julius Emspak to Jack Fletcher Regarding Bonding, February 4, 1943; 2.
      - Emspak to Irma Locke Regarding Charter, March 3, 1943; 3.
      - Emspak to H. Pearce Regarding Waiver, February 16, 1945; 4.
      - Secretary of Emspak to J. Grierson, February 7, 1947; 5.
      - Emspak to Allchin Regarding Newspaper, December 19, 1949; 6.
      - Emspak to George Wallace Regarding Leaflet, May 27, 1953; 7.
      - George Harris to Grierson Regarding Membership, Febuary 24, 1947; 8.
      - Leo Jandreau to Carl Signorotti Regarding Worker Unity, July 9, 1954; 9.
      - James Matles to C. Sullivan Regarding Report, October 3, 1949; 10.
      - Matles to Signorotti Regarding Union Support, July 15, 1954; 11.
    - Local 524 Outgoing Correspondence, 1944 - 1955 (Box 6, Folder 142)
      - Roger Allchin to UE News Service Regarding Supplies, December 8, 1949; 1.
      - Allchin to Julius Emspak Regarding Paper Publication, December 8, 1949; 2.
      - Kathleen Casey to Emspak Regarding Address Change, May 23, 1947; 3.
      - A. Cress to Emspak Regarding Supplies, November 28, 1946; 4.
      - T. Davies to Emspak Regarding Funding, February 23, 1950; 5.
      - J. Grierson to Emspak Regarding Membership, February 4, 1947; 6.
      - N. Hamblin to Emspak Regarding Officers, January 31, 1944; 7.
      - Shirley Harris to George Harris Regarding Check, March 19, 1953; 8.
      - E. Kennedy to Emspak Regarding Check, March 19, 1953; 9.
      - Kennedy to Albert Fitzgerald Regarding Anti-McCarthyism, May 31, 1955; 10.
      - St. Lamot to Emspak Regarding Convention, August 27, 1943; 11.
      - Jean Leslie Letter Regarding Supplies, undated; 12.
      - H. Pearce to Emspak Regarding Waiver, February 6, 1945; 13.
      - Alex Seppala to Emspak Regarding Finances, February 27, 1950; 14.
      - Carl Signorotti to Leo Jandreau Regarding Corruption, July 13, 1954; 15.
      - C. Sullivan to James Matles Regarding International Convention, September 30, 1949; 16.
      - George Wallace to Emspak Regarding Defeated IUE Raiders, September 18, 1952; 17.
      - Wallace to Emspak Regarding Strike Vote, May 7 1953; 18.
      - Letter Regarding Unionism, undated; 19.
    - Local 524 Financial Voucher, January 30, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 143)
    - Local 524 Correspondence, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 144)
      - Julius Emspak to C.S. Jackson, April 7, 1943; 1.
      - Jackson to Emspak, October 14, 1943; 2.
      - Emspak to Jackson, October 18, 1943; 3.
      - Jackson to Emspak, October 19, 1943; 4.
      - Leo Jandreau to Jackson, October 22, 1943; 5.
    - Local 524 Charter Reissuance Correspondence, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 145)
      - Julius Emspak to George Harris, May 14, 1946; 1.
      - Harris to Emspak, May 14, 1946; 2.
      - Emspak to Harris, May 16, 1946; 3.
      - Harris to Emspak, May 21, 1946; 4.
      - Emspak to C.S. Jackson, May 27, 1946; 5.
      - Emspak to Harris, May 27, 1946; 6.
      - Emspak to Harris, July 29, 1946; 7.
    - Local 524 Financial Correspondence, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 146)
      - C.S. Jackson to James Matles, February 25, 1950; 1.
      - Matles to Jackson, March 1, 1950; 2.
    - Local 524 Correspondence, George Harris to Julius Emspak Regarding Book Club, November 27, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 147)
    - Local 524 Press Release, May 30, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 148)
  - Local 525
    - Local 525 Officers Lists, November 22, 1943-September 9, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 149)
    - Local 525 Incoming Correspondence, 1945 - 1947 (Box 6, Folder 150)
      - Julius Emspak to W. Hislop Regarding Bonding, March 27, 1945; 1.
      - Emspak to Hislop Regarding Supplies, June 14, 1945; 2.
      - Emspak to Hislop, November 7, 1945; 3.
      - Emspak to Robert Prentice Regarding Union Procedure, November 10, 1947; 4.
    - Local 525 Outgoing Correspondence, 1943-1948 (Box 6, Folder 151)
      - J. Beal to UE Regarding Check, July 7, 1947; 1.
      - E. Colby to Julius Emspak Regarding Officers, November 23, 1943; 2.
      - W. Hislop to UE Regarding Supplies, June 11, 1945; 3.
      - Hislop to Emspak Regarding Membership Campaign, October 31, 1945; 4.
      - Hislop to Emspak Regarding Order, January 25, 1946; 5.
      - Robert Prentice to Emspak Regarding Supplies, October 30, 1947; 6.
      - Prentice to Emspak Regarding Check, June 16, 1948; 7.
    - Local 525 Financial Receipts, July 12, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 152)
    - Local 525 Organization, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 153)
      - C.S. Jackson to Julius Emspak, October 19, 1943; 1.
      - Emspak to Jackson, October 20, 1943; 2-3.
    - Local 525 Correspondence, 1943 - 1950 (Box 6, Folder 154)
      - Julius Emspak to C.S. Jackson Regarding Membership Drive, November 7, 1945; 1.
      - W. Hislop to Lilian Rosenbert Regarding Strikes, August 9, 1950; 2.
  - Local 526
    - Local 526 Officers Lists, March 9 - July 8, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 155)
    - Local 526 Incoming Correspondence, 1943 - 1947 (Box 6, Folder 156)
      - Julius Emspak to Harry Peace Regarding Charter, October 25, 1943; 1.
      - Emspak to Peace Regarding Bonding, October 25, 1943; 2.
      - Emspak to Leidda Yates Regarding Per Capita, October 29, 1945; 3.
    - Local 526 Outgoing Correspondence, 1944, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 157)
      - Bessie Harrison Letter Regarding Constitution, June 18, 1944; 1.
      - Leidda Yates Letter Regarding Supplies, October 7, 1946; 2.
    - Local 526 Organization, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 158)
      - Esther Steele to Julius Emspak, October 20, 1943; 1.
      - Julius Emspak to C.S. Jackson, October 25, 1943; 2.
    - Local 526 Disbanding and IBEW, 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 159)
      - Julius Emspak to C.S. Jackson, October 16, 1946; 1.
      - Jackson to Emspak, October 18, 1946; 2.
      - Emspak to Jackson, February 28, 1947; 3.
  - Local 526 (Carbaloy)
    - Local 526 (Carbaloy) Organization, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 160)
      - Ross Russell to Julius Emspak, August 18, 1948; 1.
      - Emspak to Russell, August 27, 1948; 2.
      - Emspak to C.S. Jackson, August 27, 1948; 3.
  - Local 527
    - Local 527 Incoming Correspondence, 1944-1946 (Box 6, Folder 161)
      - Julius Emspak to Harold Collins Regarding Waiver, April 30, 1945; 1.
      - Emspak to D. Drummond Regarding Bonding, December 11, 1946; 2.
      - C. Jackson to Rupert Starr Regarding Supplies, April 12, 1944; 3.
    - Local 527 Outgoing Correspondence, H. Collins to Julius Emspak Regarding Resolutions, April 25, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 162)
    - Local 527 Organization, Julius Emspak to Ellis Blair and C.S. Jackson, December 30, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 163)
    - Local 527 Financial Plan, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 164)
      - C.S. Jackson to Julius Emspak, April 12, 1944; 1.
      - Emspak to Jackson, May 8, 1944; 2.
    - Local 527 Ontario Labor Relations Board, 1945 - 1946 (Box 6, Folder 165)
      - J.P. Nicol to UE, March 9, 1945; 1.
      - Julius Emspak to Nicol, March 12, 1945; 2.
      - D.W. Mather to UE, June 8, 1946; 3.
      - Emspak to Mather, June 10, 1946; 4.
    - Local 527 Correspondence, Julius Emspak to George Harris, April 30, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 166)
  - Local 528
    - Local 528 Officers List, January 22, 1947 - July 3, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 167)
    - Local 528 Incoming Correspondence, Julius Emspak to W. Currie Regarding Supplies, May 28, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 168)
    - Local 528 Outgoing Correspondence, 1944, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 169)
      - M. Boldue to Julius Emspak Regarding Supplies, October 31, 1944; 1.
      - Marcel Gagnon to Emspak Regarding Expelled Members, February 26, 1947; 2.
    - Local 528 Termination of Strike with Phillips Electric, April 11, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 170)
  - Local 529
    - Local 529 Incoming Correspondence, 1945 - 1948 (Box 6, Folder 171)
      - Julius Emspak to Leonard Velleman Regarding Waiver, January 23, 1945; 1.
      - Emspak to E. Rinker Regarding Bonding, July 17, 1947; 2.
      - Emspak to Alan Smith Regarding Contract, June 7, 1948; 3.
      - Emspak to J. Gray Regarding Charter, August 27, 1948; 4.
    - Local 529 Outgoing Correspondence, 1945 - 1948 (Box 6, Folder 172)
      - L. Chevers to UE Regarding Bonding, August 17, 1944; 1.
      - J. Gray to Julius Emspak Regarding Charter, August 20, 1948; 2.
      - E. Rinker to Emspak Regarding Bonding, June 21, 1947; 3.
      - Alan Smith to Emspak Regarding Supplies, May 21, 1948; 4.
      - Leondard Velleman to Emspak Regarding Audit Reports, January 6, 1945; 5.
      - Vellemen to Emspak Regarding Supplies, January 15, 1945; 6.
    - Local 529 Organization at Packard and English Electric, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 173)
      - C.S. Jackson to Julius Emspak, May 12, 1944; 1.
      - Emspak to C.R. Sullivan, May 21, 1944; 2.
      - Emspak to Jackson, May 21, 1944; 3.
      - Emspak to Albert Olson, August 22, 1944; 4.
      - M.M. Maclean to Emspak with a National Labor Relations Board Brief, October 27, 1944; 5.
    - Local 529 Organization at Yale and Towne, 1946 - 1947 (Box 6, Folder 174)
      - D.W. Mather ot UE, July 16, 1946; 1.
      - Julius Emspak to Mather, July 23, 1946; 2.
      - Ross Russell to James Matles, March 28, 1947; 3.
  - Local 530
    - Local 530 Officers List, March 18, 1947 - March 3, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 175)
    - Local 530 Incoming Correspondence, Julius Emspak to Peter Matler Regarding Officers, September 9, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 176)
    - Local 530 Outgoing Correspondence, 1947, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 177)
      - P. Pawliuk to Julius Emspak Regarding Constitution, October 12, 1949; 1.
      - Mary Radigk to UE News Regarding Supplies, September 13, 1947; 2.
    - Local 530 Delinquency Notices, October - December 30, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 178)
    - Local 530 Organization, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 179)
      - Julius Emspak to Ross Russell, April 22, 1946; 1.
      - Emspak to C.S. Jackson, April 22, 1946; 2.
      - Russell to Emspak, April 22, 1946; 3-4.
      - Emspak to Russell, April 22, 1946; 5.
      - P.W. Mather to UE, April 25, 1946; 6.
      - Emspak to D.W. Mather, April 30, 1946; 7.
  - Local 531
    - Local 531 Officers Lists, April 14, 1947 - July 10, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 180)
    - Local 531 Incoming Correspondence, Julius Emspak to Rae Mackie Regarding Supplies, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 181)
    - Local 531 Outgoing Correspondence, 1946 - 1948 (Box 6, Folder 182)
      - O. Levesque to James Matles Regarding Taft-Hartley Bill, July 29, 1947; 1.
      - Rae Mackie to Julius Emspak Regarding Supplies, November 2, 1946; 2.
      - Mackie Letter Regarding Supplies, No Date; 3.
      - Leo Roback to Matles Regarding Publications, March 25, 1948; 4.
    - Local 531 Delinquencies, May - August 7, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 183)
    - Local 531 Financial Ledger, undated (Box 6, Folder 184)
    - Local 531 Organization, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 185)
      - Secretary of Julius Emspak to C.S. Jackson, October 11, 1946; 1.
      - Secretary of Albert Fitzgerald to Leonard Brothers, October 21, 1946; 2.
      - Ray Klausner to Jackson, November 11, 1946; 3.
      - George Harris to Emspak, November 27, 1946; 4.
      - Emspak to Jackson, November 29, 1946; 5.
    - Local 531 Per Capita, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 186)
      - Goerge Harris to Julius Emspak, January 9, 1947; 1.
      - Emspak to Harris, January 21, 1947; 2.
      - Harris to Emspak, January 24, 1947; 3.
      - Emspak to Harris, Febuary 3, 1947; 4.
  - Local 532
    - Local 532 Organization, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 187)
      - Julius Emspak to Ross Russell, September 12, 1950; 1.
      - George Harris to Emspak, October 2, 1950; 2.
  - Local 533
    - Local 533 Officers Lists, August 1, 1947 - March 3, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 188)
    - Local 533 Incoming Correspondence, Julius Emspak to N. Hamblin Regarding Supplies, October 31, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 189)
    - Local 533 Delinquency Notices, November 1951 - Febuary 21, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 190)
    - Local 533 Organization, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 191)
      - C.S. Jackson to Julius Emspak, July 28, 1947; 1.
      - Emspak to Jackson, August 12, 1947; 2.
      - Emspak to N. Hamblin, August 12, 1947; 3.
    - Local 533 Correspondence Regarding Suspensions, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 192)
      - Julius Emspak to George Harris, January 28, 1952; 1.
      - Emspak to George Harris, March 24, 1952; 2.
    - Local 533 Correspondence, W.R. Camber to Publicity Department Regarding Supplies, March 24, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 193)
  - Local 534
    - Local 534 Officers Lists, May 14, 1948 - November 14, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 194)
    - Local 534 Outgoing Correspondence, R. Higginson to Julius Emspak Regarding New Secretary, August 31, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 195)
    - Local 534 Correspondence, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 196)
      - Julius Emspak to C.S. Jackson, May 14, 1948; 1.
      - Jackson to Emspak, May 14, 1948; 2.
      - Emspak to Jackson, May 17, 1948; 3.
      - George Harris to Emspak, May 20, 1948; 4.
      - Emspak to Harris, May 28, 1948; 5.
      - Harris to Emspak, October 4, 1948; 6.
  - Local 535
    - Local 535 Incoming Correspondence, Julius Emspak to G. Ettinger Regarding Bonding, September 24, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 197)
    - Local 535 Organization, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 198)
      - C.S. Jackson to Julius Emspak, June 25, 1948; 1.
      - Emspak to Jackson, July 1, 1948; 2.
      - Ross Russell to Emspak, August 17, 1948; 3.
  - Local 536
    - Local 536 Officers Lists, September 15, 1948 - September 30, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 199)
    - Local 536 Incoming Correspondence, 1948-1953 (Box 6, Folder 200)
      - Julius Emspak to Alex Clarry Regarding Bonding, September 24, 1948; 1.
      - Emspak to F. Holton Regarding Forms, September 27, 1949; 2.
      - Emspak to R. Smart Regarding Address Change, March 23, 1950; 3.
      - Emspak to Jim Salfi Regarding Supplies, February 26, 1953; 4.
    - Local 536 Outgoing Correspondence, 1949 - 1950 (Box 6, Folder 201)
      - James Duncan Letter Regarding New Secretary, June 1, 1949; 1.
      - A. McKnight Letter Regarding Check, February 13, 1950; 2.
      - Jane Scott Letter Regarding Change of Address, January 4, 1950; 3.
    - Local 536 Delinquency and Suspension Notices, July - October 21, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 202)
    - Local 536 Per Capita Report, February 14, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 203)
    - Local 536 Per Capita Forms, September 1946 - May 1950 (Box 6, Folder 204)
    - Local 536 Organization, 1948-1949 (Box 6, Folder 205)
      - Ross Russell to Julius Emspak, July 12, 1948; 1.
      - Emspak to Russell, July 13, 1948; 2.
      - L. Harries to Emspak, July 19, 1948; 3.
      - Russell to Emspak, August 17, 1948; 4.
      - D.W. Mather to UE, September 1, 1948; 5.
      - Emspak to Mather, September 13, 1948; 6.
      - P.M. Draber to UE, October 4, 1948; 7.
      - Emspak to Draber, October 11, 1948; 8.
      - C.S. Jackson to Emspak, December 17, 1948; 9.
      - George Harris to Emspak, January 14, 1949; 11.
    - Local 536 Correspondence, Julius Emspak to George Harris Regarding Suspensions, November 27, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 206)
  - Local 536 (Niagara Falls)
    - Local 536 (Niagara Falls) Organization, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 207)
      - Ross Russell to Julius Emspak, Febuary 18, 1953; 1.
      - Emspak to Russell, February 26, 1953; 2.
      - Emspak to C.S. Jackson, February 26, 1953; 3.
      - Russell to Emspak, March 2, 1953; 4.
  - Local 537
    - Local 537 Incoming Correspondence, Julius Emspak to Ruby Jones Regarding Charters, February 17, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 208)
    - Local 537 Organization, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 209)
      - Ross Russell to Julius Emspak, February 15, 1949; 1.
      - Emspak to Russell, February 17, 1949; 2.
      - Emspak to C.S. Jackson, February 17, 1949; 3.
  - Local 538
    - Local 538 Officers Lists, June 14, 1949 - March 9, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 210)
    - Local 538 Incoming Correspondence, Julius Emspak to John Bettes Regarding Charter, November 11, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 211)
    - Local 538 Shipment Log, June 28, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 212)
    - Local 538 Organization, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 213)
      - George Harris to Julius Emspak, June 16, 1949; 1.
      - Emspak to Harris, June 21, 1949; 2-3.
  - Local 538 (Etobicoke)
    - Local 538 (Etobicoke) Organization, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 214)
      - Ross Russell to Julius Emspak, November 4, 1953; 1.
      - Russell to Emspak, November 6, 1953; 2.
  - Local 540
    - Local 540 IUE Inter-union Rivalry, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 215)
      - George Harris to Julius Emspak, January 17, 1950; 1.
      - Emspak to Harris, January 18, 1950; 2.
      - Harris to Emspak, January 30, 1950; 3.
      - Emspak to Harris, February 1, 1950; 4.
  - Local 541
    - Local 541 Organization, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 216)
      - Ross Russell to Julius Emspak, May 26, 1954; 1.
      - Albert Fitzgerald to C.S. Jackson, June 2, 1954; 2.
      - Emspak to Russell, June 4, 1954; 3.
      - Emspak to Russell, July 14, 1954; 4.
      - Russell to Emspak, July 20, 1954; 5.
  - Local 542
    - Local 542 Incoming Correspondence, Julius Emspak to Joseph Crouch Regarding Charter, March 7, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 217)
    - Local 542 Organization, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 218)
      - Ross Russell to Julius Emspak, February 10, 1955; 1.
      - Emspak to Russell, February 16, 1955; 2.
      - Russell to Emspak, February 23, 1955; 3.
      - Russell to UE, February 28, 1955; 4.
      - Emspak to N. Choate, March 2, 1955; 5.
      - Russell to Emspak, March 3, 1955; 6.
      - Russell to Emspak, March 7, 1955; 7.
  - Local 544
    - Local 544 Incoming Correspondence, Julius Emspak to John Cook Regarding Charter, January 10, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 219)
    - Local 544 Organization, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 220)
      - Ross Russell to Julius Emspak, January 4, 1955; 1.
      - Emspak to Russell, January 10, 1955; 2.
  - Local 550
    - Local 550 Correspondence, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 221)